Muhammad Zahid Tufail

Electrical Engineer (Registered with PEC)



Contact

Summary

MS in Electrical Engineering (Signal & Image Processing)

Industrial Experience - 1 year Currently Teaching in College (Jinnah Polytechnic Institute)

Contact:

0092-332-6750867 zahid.tufail10@gmail.com Faisalabad, Pakistan



Objective:

"With an MS degree in Electrical Engineering and a hand on experience of more than one year in industry & education sector. My goal is to find a full-time Electrical Engineering position where I may be able to give my best effort to achieve targets."

* Qualification:

2015-2018	MS Signal & Image Processing	IST Islamabad	3.63
2010-2014	BSc Electrical Engineering	UET Lahore	2.88
2008-2010	FSc	BISE Faisalabad	78.81%
2005-2007	Martic	BISE Faisalabad	78%

Experience:

Teaching:

Lecturer Jinnah Polytechnic Institute (May, 2018 - Continue)

• Teaching BS Technology Classes

Signal & Systems Electric Machines

▶ Lecturer Laboratory College of Technology (Session 2017 - 2018)

Subjects

Electrical Instruments and Measurements DC Machine
Business Management Basic Electronics

Industrial:

➤ 1 Year Management Associate in PTCL (March 2016 - March 2017)

Responsibilities

Staff Management Fault Control Cable Quality Test
CSR & CPEI Support CRM Operation Official e-mail reporting
Equipment Renovation Customer Help Customer Feedback

***** Publications:

> Journal

*IEEE Access:*DOI: 10.1109/access.2018.2843261
Improved Dark Channel Prior for Image Defogging using RGB and YCbCr
Color Space

> Conference

International:

Future Technologies Conference (FTC) 2018 in Vancouver (Technically sponsored by IEEE)

* Projects:

> MS Thesis: (Image Defogging)

My MS thesis topic was Image defogging, I did research on removing fog from image data and reconstructed fog-free images. My research was based on Dark Channel Prior. I proposed method to calculate transmission map which was used to reconstruct image.

> BS Project: (Robotic Lawn Mower)

In this project I learnt to control device by feedback control system, Programming on Arduino, interfacing different sensors & actuators and troubleshooting of circuit.

❖ Software Experience: ❖ Skills:

Matlab, Proteus (ISIS ARES), Management, Technical Reporting, Keil µvision, Electronics Workbench, Circuit Designing and Troubleshooting, Xilinx, MS Office Programming skills, Research work,

Contact & Mailing Address:

zahid.tufail10@gmail.com 03326750867

House No. P-82, Aminabad No.1, Main Road Samanabad, Faisalabad, Pakistan